Shahryar Soltanpour

(403) 827-9737 shahryar.soltanpour@gmail.com

Software Engineer

Portfolio: sh-soltanpour.github.io github.com/sh-soltanpour linkedin.com/in/soltanpour

SUMMARY

Experienced software engineer with a 4-year track record in the industry. Adept in back-end development and knowledgeable in front-end development, data engineering, databases, and SRE, resulting in a comprehensive understanding of system design and the ability to design, implement, and deploy software systems from scratch.

SKILLS

Programming Languages Python, Java, Kotlin, Bash, Javascript, C++

Software Engineering Object-Oriented patterns, Agile (scrum) and DevOps methodologies

Site Reliability Engineering Docker, Kubernetes, HA Proxy, Nginx, Linux

Big data / databases Cassandra, Kafka, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Elasticsearch, Redis

Web Django, Spring boot, Express.JS, HTTP, REST

Tools Git, JUnit, IntelliJ IDEA, LTFX

Frontend React, Angular Languages English, Persian

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Aug 2019 — Dec 2020

Divar Company Iran

- Developed various features such as infinite scrolling using Python, Django, PostgreSQL, and Redis.
- Deployed the implemented features on the cloud using **Docker** and **Kubernetes**.
- Maintained services to ensure the owned services are operating properly 24/7. Working closely with **Grafana** and **Kubernetes**.
- Reviewed and evaluated merge requests on my owned services then merge and deploy them.
- Designed the system for new features, by writing design docs and implementing them.
- Interviewed and helped select software engineers.

Software Engineer

Jun 2018 — Aug 2019

Mediaad (Tapsell Company)

- Designed and implemented a video player platform with ad integration for website owners, coded frontend using **Angular** and backend using **Kotlin**, **Spring Boot**, and **MongoDB**, and deployed using **Docker** and **Kubernetes**.
- Designed and implemented a system to extract useful information based on the videos watched in the mentioned video player, using Kafka, Elasticsearch, and Kibana.
- Implemented the *retargeting* feature that increased click-through rate by 10x, the conversion rate by 70%. Resulting in 10 times more chances to be clicked through and this caused a very significant increase in the company's revenue. **Kafka** and **CassandraDB** were the main components of this feature.

Software Engineer Jan 2018 — Jun 2018

Backtory (Tapsell Company)

Iran

- · Backtory is a CDN, Storage, and video streaming service.
- Refactored CDN service codebase and update the programming from Java to Kotlin.
- Tested various tools for load balancing to find the best method for our usage, such as HAProxy.
- Implemented features such as the ability to provide custom 404 error pages for each CDN user using Nginx, Kotlin, and Spring Boot.

Software Engineer Intern

Jul 2017 — Aug 2017

Iran

• Launched *Unaqi*, a location-based social network application. Developed iOS and Android applications using react native.

- Developed backend using Node JS Express.
- Learned how to use **Git**, and **Scrum** methodology in a team.
- Source Code: Backend and Frontend

Rahnema College (Rahnema Company)

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computer Science, University of Calgary

Jan 2021 — Present

GPA: 3.85 / 4

Bachelor of science in Computer Engineering, *University of Tehran*

Sep 2015 — Jun 2020

Shahryar Soltanpour

(403) 827-9737 shahryar.soltanpour@gmail.com

Software Engineer

Portfolio: sh-soltanpour.github.io github.com/sh-soltanpour linkedin.com/in/soltanpour

NOTABLE PROJECTS

- Implemented a compiler for an actor-based language named Atalk in the compiler design course using **Antlr4** and **Java**. (Source Code)
- Implemented a web-based freelancing application for the Internet Engineering course. Using Java Servlets for the backend and React.JS for frontend (Source Code: Backend and Frontend)
- Implemented a crawler and data analysis tool on the Lululemon website as the main project of the Datamining and Social Network course using **Scrapy**, **Gephi**, and **Networkx**. (Source code)
- Implemented Splitwise application using smart contracts using technologies such as **Truffle**, **Solidity** language, and **web3.js** (Source Code)

EXTRACURRICULAR

• President of Computer Science Graduate Society, University of Calgary

May 2021 — May 2022

• Graduate Student Council Representative, University of Calgary

May 2021 — May 2022

• **Technical mentor** in the summer of code event, University of Tehran

Jul 2018 — Sep 2018

Teach Nginx, Spring boot, and Kotlin to mentees to develop a file storage application for university students.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Graduate Research

Jan 2021 — Present

University of Calgary

Canada

• Investigated the use of multilingual codes, especially in industry, and also maintained a change propagation framework written in C#. This framework supports multiple languages such as Java, C#, Python, and Transact-SQL. In addition, developed a system to guess the language of the input string based on keyword usage and then evaluate the guess using the language grammar.

Undergraduate Research

Jul 2019 — Oct 2019

University of Tehran

Iran

Used java language to compile and run Rebeca codes with different policies and measure some metrics to find the best
algorithm. Rebeca (Reactive Objects Language) is an actor-based language with a formal foundation, designed in an effort to
bridge the gap between formal verification approaches and real applications. It can be considered a reference model for
concurrent computation, based on an operational interpretation of the actor model. It is also a platform for developing
object-based concurrent systems in practice.

TEACHING ASSISTANTSHIP

Introduction to Software Engineering

Winter 2021, 2022, 2023, Fall 2022

University of Calgary

Oversaw group projects for 3 tutorial sessions (Each containing 28 students)

Web based systems

Fall 2022

University of Calgary

• Oversaw group projects for 1 tutorial session (Containing 25 students)

Internet Engineering

Spring 2020

University of Tehran

• Chief TA of the course. Managing all course projects to be designed, delivered, and evaluated.

Systems Analysis and Design

Spring 2019

University of Tehran

• Chief TA of the course. Managing course projects, quizzes, and homework.